<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<django-objects version="1.0"><object pk="2" model="ctp_website.series"><field type="CharField" name="name">Currie&amp; Quirk Shostakovich Series</field><field type="CharField" name="bio"></field><field type="CharField" name="url">shost</field><field type="CharField" name="image_url"></field><field type="IntegerField" name="image_width">400</field><field type="CharField" name="image_credit"></field></object><object pk="3" model="ctp_website.series"><field type="CharField" name="name">Cottier Dance Project</field><field type="CharField" name="bio">&lt;p&gt;The Cottier Dance Project is the dance programme of the Chamber Project.  After a successful pilot year in 2014, The Dance Project has expanded its programme for 2015, and will continue to champion Scottish-based choreographers and dancers, to provide a platform for new work and to forge new collaborations across the arts to create and develop original performance pieces. As well as contemporary, commissioned work, there will also be a focus on archival dance footage and arts film, so that great and inspirational work from the past can be revisited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are delighted to be using Cottier’s Theatre, The Western Baths and the Grosvenor Cinema as our host venues, with the programme including live performances of contemporary, aerial, tango and street dance, music and dance collaborations, screenings of archive and independent dance film.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For full programme information please see the Programme page, or click on the calendar.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The Cottier Dance Project is curated by Freya Jeffs, with support from the Cottier Chamber Project team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style="margin-left:50px"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Freya Jeffs&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://www.dcs.gla.ac.uk/~srogers/freya.jpg" style="float:right;" width="200px"&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Freya trained at Elmhurst and Central School of Ballet, appearing in various productions with The Royal Ballet, English National Ballet and Birmingham Royal Ballet. In 2006 she joined Ballet Central, performing in works by Rafael Bonachela, Will Tuckett, and creating a role in Christopher Bruce's Shift. Freya then joined Scottish Ballet for Ashley Page's productions of Sleeping Beauty, Nutcracker and Pastor's Romeo and Juliet. During her time in Scotland she has toured nationally with Errol White Company (IAM), Company Chordelia (Les Amoureux), and worked extensively with Articulate Animal, including the interactive performance of Blowup with visual artist Simon Biggs. Freya has also worked with Theatre Cryptic (Sound to Sea), All or Nothing Aerial Dance Theatre (Three’s a Crowd), Ruth Mills Dance and Stephen Pelton Dance Theatre.  

Her film-based dance projects include; ‘It for Others’ by Duncan Campbell – winner of The Turner Prize 2014 and created for the Venice Biennale Festival 2013, choreographed by Michael Clark; ‘Traces of Places’ collaboration with Articulate Animal and Director Roddy Simpson – part of DANCE:FILM 11 and screened internationally.  Music video credits include Zulu Winter, John Cale, The Japanese Popstars and feature film Sunshine on Leith.  

Projects involving collaborations with live musicians include &lt;i&gt;Two’s Company, Dance and Music&lt;/i&gt; at the Cheltenham Festival, where she danced to Finzi’s Clarinet Concerto, Bach and Walton, and &lt;i&gt;re-memberings&lt;/i&gt; with ‘the other ensemble’ for DanceLive and Fringe festivals.  In 2014 she performed with High Heart Dance Company in collaboration with Traditional Musician of the Year Emily Smith, Jamie McClennan and band in &lt;/i&gt;Footprints&lt;/i&gt;, as part of the Made in Scotland Showcase, and also created &lt;i&gt;The Lady of Shalott&lt;/i&gt; with chamber ensemble Daniel’s Beard for the same showcase.  2015 will see her perform again with Daniel’s Beard in a new work, and with Stephen Pelton Dance Theater alongside The Gavin Bryars Ensemble.

Freya has worked with Stockport Youth Orchestra to encourage and educate young musicians to compose music for dance.  She has taught ballet, contemporary, floor barre and musicality based classes at various professional establishments including Royal Conservatoire of Scotland, Scottish Ballet and Dance House Glasgow. &lt;p&gt;
</field><field type="CharField" name="url">dance</field><field type="CharField" name="image_url"></field><field type="IntegerField" name="image_width">400</field><field type="CharField" name="image_credit"></field></object><object pk="4" model="ctp_website.series"><field type="CharField" name="name">Lunchtime Lieder</field><field type="CharField" name="bio">at the Hunterian Museum</field><field type="CharField" name="url">lieder</field><field type="CharField" name="image_url"></field><field type="IntegerField" name="image_width">400</field><field type="CharField" name="image_credit"></field></object><object pk="5" model="ctp_website.series"><field type="CharField" name="name">Late Adventures</field><field type="CharField" name="bio"></field><field type="CharField" name="url">lateadventures</field><field type="CharField" name="image_url"></field><field type="IntegerField" name="image_width">400</field><field type="CharField" name="image_credit"></field></object><object pk="6" model="ctp_website.series"><field type="CharField" name="name">The Cottier Jazz Project</field><field type="CharField" name="bio">in collaboration with the Glasgow International Jazz Festival</field><field type="CharField" name="url">jazz</field><field type="CharField" name="image_url"></field><field type="IntegerField" name="image_width">400</field><field type="CharField" name="image_credit"></field></object><object pk="7" model="ctp_website.series"><field type="CharField" name="name">Performer Portraits</field><field type="CharField" name="bio">Photographers Sean Purser and Mikah Smillie, both West End residents, will be taking portrait shots of every single performer in action. Their photos will capture and freeze moments of intense concentration, emotion, communication and drama, telling the story of the festival, day by day.
The exhibition will be displayed in the front window of Waitrose, Byres Road. With new photographs being added daily, the Performer Portraits exhibition will be a growing, evolving exploration of the moments and people that make The Cottier Chamber Project special!
</field><field type="CharField" name="url">portraits</field><field type="CharField" name="image_url"></field><field type="IntegerField" name="image_width">400</field><field type="CharField" name="image_credit"></field></object><object pk="8" model="ctp_website.series"><field type="CharField" name="name">Chamber Music</field><field type="CharField" name="bio"></field><field type="CharField" name="url"></field><field type="CharField" name="image_url"></field><field type="IntegerField" name="image_width">400</field><field type="CharField" name="image_credit"></field></object><object pk="9" model="ctp_website.series"><field type="CharField" name="name">Films</field><field type="CharField" name="bio">Glasgow's West End is missing a large-stage theatre, complete with fly tower, wings and orchestra pit.  Luckily, we do have a fantastic independent cinema and a whole list of films and archive footage that we would like to see...</field><field type="CharField" name="url">film</field><field type="CharField" name="image_url"></field><field type="IntegerField" name="image_width">400</field><field type="CharField" name="image_credit"></field></object></django-objects>