<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<django-objects version="1.0"><object pk="1" model="ctp_website.venue"><field type="CharField" name="name">Cottier's Theatre</field><field type="CharField" name="address">93-95 Hyndland Street, Glasgow. G11 5PU</field><field type="CharField" name="contact_number">empty</field><field type="CharField" name="image_url">empty</field><field type="CharField" name="image_url2">http://www.dcs.gla.ac.uk/~srogers/cottiermap.jpg</field><field type="CharField" name="image_url3">empty</field><field type="IntegerField" name="image_width">200</field><field type="IntegerField" name="image_width2">400</field><field type="IntegerField" name="image_width3">100</field><field type="CharField" name="image_credit">Andy</field><field type="CharField" name="image_credit2">empty</field><field type="CharField" name="image_credit3">empty</field><field type="CharField" name="info">The Cottier Chamber Project began in Cottier's with a short pilot-series given by Daniel's Beard in 2010.  The theatre, bar and restaurant are housed in the former Dowanhill Parish Church, which was built in 1865 by William Leiper.  The interior decoration and beautiful stained glass were by Daniel Cottier, whose portrait hangs in the bar (and inspired the name of host ensemble Daniel's Beard!).  Much of the decoration was either covered up or desperately in need of expert conservation, so Four Acres Charitable Trust was set up to run the building and to co-ordinate and supervise the restoration process.  Following a period of major structural work, the theatre reopened in 2011, though as the restoration work was on-going, much of the decoration was hidden from view.  For this year's series, we're delighted that the theatre (housed in the actual church) is nearing Daniel Cottier's original decor, and the magnificent Willis Organ has been restored and re-installed.

The bar and restaurant continue to operate from the old church hall, with a revamped menu focussing on local, fresh ingredients.  The decor is Cottier-esque in style, and the profits from the bar and restaurant go towards continuing the conservation work, so take advantage of the chance to have a pint at a concert and then make use of your discount on the barbeque menu!

Cottier’s is one of the main performance spaces for the West End Festival.  The Cottier Chamber Project will hold concerts daily (except for Saturdays) on the 6th – 20th June, and The Cottier Dance Project will run from the 23rd – 27th June.

Click &lt;a href="http://www.cottiers.com" target="new"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to visit the website for Cottier’s and find out more about the history of the building and the restoration work that is taking place.</field><field type="CharField" name="url">cottiers</field><field type="CharField" name="nearest_subway"><None></None></field><field type="CharField" name="nearest_bus"><None></None></field><field type="CharField" name="google_maps"><None></None></field></object><object pk="2" model="ctp_website.venue"><field type="CharField" name="name">St. Silas Church</field><field type="CharField" name="address">69 Park Road, Glasgow, Lanarkshire G4 9JE</field><field type="CharField" name="contact_number">empty</field><field type="CharField" name="image_url">empty</field><field type="CharField" name="image_url2">http://www.dcs.gla.ac.uk/~srogers/stsilasmap.jpg</field><field type="CharField" name="image_url3">empty</field><field type="IntegerField" name="image_width">400</field><field type="IntegerField" name="image_width2">600</field><field type="IntegerField" name="image_width3">100</field><field type="CharField" name="image_credit">empty</field><field type="CharField" name="image_credit2">empty</field><field type="CharField" name="image_credit3">empty</field><field type="CharField" name="info">One of the busiest churches in the West End, St Silas was founded in 1864 as an independent Anglican congregation.  The original trustees included Sir George Burns, one of the founders of the Cunard Company, William Burnley, who owned much of the land on which the sea-side resort of Dunoon was then being developed, and Sir Archibald Campbell of Blythswood.
 
For over a century, all services were conducted using the 1662 Prayer Book. For most of that time, this liturgy was regarded as central to the maintenance of the church’s distinctive evangelical doctrine. However, in the 1970’s the church decided that liturgies in modern English were also needed. This was a decision with significant financial consequences, since it involved relinquishing a significant source of income, the Blythswood bequest.

Now part of the Scottish Episcopal Church, St Silas is very active in the local community and in recent years, the church has carried out a series of improvements to the church building. This continues with the current new church hall project, “Building for the Future”.  The congregation is a lively mix of ages and backgrounds, with an aim of being a church that helps people ‘live life in all its fullness' (John 10:10).

This is the first time that The Cottier Chamber Project has used St Silas as a venue, and we are thoroughly looking forward to holding 5 concerts there on Saturday 7th and Saturday 14th June.  The church will also host several other events during the &lt;a href ="http://www.westendfestival.co.uk/" target="new"&gt;West End Festival&lt;/a&gt;, including a special event for the Gibson Street Gala.

&lt;a href ="http://www.stsilas.org.uk/" target="new"&gt;Church homepage&lt;/a&gt;</field><field type="CharField" name="url">stsilas</field><field type="CharField" name="nearest_subway"><None></None></field><field type="CharField" name="nearest_bus"><None></None></field><field type="CharField" name="google_maps"><None></None></field></object><object pk="3" model="ctp_website.venue"><field type="CharField" name="name">Hunterian Art Gallery</field><field type="CharField" name="address">University of Glasgow,
82 Hillhead Street,
Glasgow.
G12 8QQ</field><field type="CharField" name="contact_number">+44 (0) 141 330 4221</field><field type="CharField" name="image_url">http://www.museumsgalleriesscotland.org.uk/site/uploads/member/large/dbddf0d57a4cfac41563216814573af3.jpg</field><field type="CharField" name="image_url2">http://www.dcs.gla.ac.uk/~srogers/hunterianmap.jpg</field><field type="CharField" name="image_url3">empty</field><field type="IntegerField" name="image_width">200</field><field type="IntegerField" name="image_width2">600</field><field type="IntegerField" name="image_width3">100</field><field type="CharField" name="image_credit">empty</field><field type="CharField" name="image_credit2">empty</field><field type="CharField" name="image_credit3">empty</field><field type="CharField" name="info">Founded in 1807, The Hunterian is Scotland's oldest public museum and home to one of the largest collections outside the National Museums. The Hunterian is one of the leading university museums in the UK and its collections have been recognised as a Collection of National Significance. It is one of Scotland’s most important cultural assets.

Built on Dr William Hunter’s founding bequest, The Hunterian collections include scientific instruments used by James Watt, Joseph Lister and Lord Kelvin; outstanding Roman artefacts from the Antonine Wall; major natural and life sciences holdings; Hunter’s own extensive anatomical teaching collection; one of the world’s greatest numismatic collections; impressive ethnographic objects from Captain Cook’s Pacific voyages and a major art collection.

The Hunterian is also home to the world’s largest permanent display of the work of James McNeill Whistler, the largest single holding of the work of Charles Rennie Mackintosh and The Mackintosh House, the reassembled interiors from his Glasgow home.  The Hunterian continues in its Age of Enlightenment mission to be a central resource for research and teaching in the arts, humanities and natural and medical sciences, attracting scholars and visitors from around the world.

There are close ties between The Cottier Chamber Project and Music in the University, so we are delighted to be holding our free lunchtime series of Bach’s solo string works in the &lt;a href ="http://www.gla.ac.uk/hunterian/about/" target="new"&gt;Hunterian Art Gallery&lt;/a&gt;.

You might also be interested in &lt;a href ="http://www.gla.ac.uk/events/musicintheuniversity/" target="new"&gt;Music in the University&lt;/a&gt;</field><field type="CharField" name="url">hunterian</field><field type="CharField" name="nearest_subway"><None></None></field><field type="CharField" name="nearest_bus"><None></None></field><field type="CharField" name="google_maps"><None></None></field></object><object pk="4" model="ctp_website.venue"><field type="CharField" name="name">Grosvenor Cinema</field><field type="CharField" name="address">24 Ashton Lane, Hillhead,
Glasgow West End,
G12 8SJ</field><field type="CharField" name="contact_number">08451666002</field><field type="CharField" name="image_url">empty</field><field type="CharField" name="image_url2">empty</field><field type="CharField" name="image_url3">empty</field><field type="IntegerField" name="image_width">400</field><field type="IntegerField" name="image_width2">200</field><field type="IntegerField" name="image_width3">100</field><field type="CharField" name="image_credit">empty</field><field type="CharField" name="image_credit2">empty</field><field type="CharField" name="image_credit3">empty</field><field type="CharField" name="info">The Grosvenor Cinema is located in the heart of the West End on Ashton Lane.  It is fully licenced, with comfy armchairs, sofas, and plenty of leg room!  

With a history of diverse programming and streaming live dance/theatre, the Grosvenor has teamed up with The West End Festival, The Cottier Chamber Project and The Cottier Dance Project, creating a rare opportunity to show popular films and rare archive footage in cinemascope.  

A 3 minute walk from Hillhead Subway, the Grosvenor houses the Lane Bar and the Grosvenor Cafe, with many other food and drink options in the immediate environs. The area is easily accessible by bus and taxi and is a 15 minute walk from Partick mainline station

Click &lt;a href=http://www.grosvenorcinema.co.uk/cinema.php&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to visit the website for the Grosvenor Cinema, Cafe and Bar.</field><field type="CharField" name="url">grosvenor</field><field type="CharField" name="nearest_subway"><None></None></field><field type="CharField" name="nearest_bus"><None></None></field><field type="CharField" name="google_maps"><None></None></field></object></django-objects>